{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Travelers, Train and Bus ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Bus and Train are different from each other but some travelers travel by bus and some travel by train."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Profit, Dividend and Bonus ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Bonus and Dividend are different from each other. But both these are parts of profit."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Women, Mothers and Engineers ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All mothers are women and some mothers and some women may be engineers."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Factory, Product and Machinery ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Product and Machinery are different from each other but both are found in Factory."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Author, Lawyer and Singer ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All the three are different professions."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Judge, Thieves and Criminals ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All the thieves are criminals while judge is different from these."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between India, Haryana and World ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Haryana is in India and India is in the World."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Pigeon, Bird and Dog ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All the pigeons are birds while dog is different from these."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Earth, Sea and Sun ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Sea is a part of Earth while Sun is different from these two."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Hockey, Football and Cricket ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All these three games are different from each other."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Iron, Lead and Nitrogen ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All these three elements are different from each other"}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Examination, Questions and Practice ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Some questions are asked in examination and some in practice but examination and practice are different from each other."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Bulb, Lamp and Light ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Bulb and Lamp are different from each other but light is obtained from both."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Lion, Dog and Snake ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All the three are different from each other."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Moon, Sun and Earth ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All the three are different from each other."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Hospital, Nurse and Patient ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Hospital consists of nurse and patient but nurse and patient are of two different nature."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Mercury, Zinc and Metal ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Mercury and Zinc both are different from one another but belong to metal."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Teacher, Writer and Musician ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A teacher may or may not be a writer and musician. Similarly a musician may or may not be a teacher and writer and so a writer may or may not be a teacher and musician."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Boys, Girls and Students ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Tall man, Black haired people and Indians ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Furniture, Chairs and Tables ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Chairs and tables both are furniture but no chair is table."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Elephant, Carnivorous and Tiger ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Tiger is carnivorous but Elephant is different from these two."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Vegetables, Tomato and Fruits ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Class, Blackboard and School ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Blackboard is in class and class is in the school."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Rabi-Crop, Paddy and Wheat ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Wheat and Paddy are different from each other but Wheat is the Rabi-Crop."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Ass, Pet and Horse ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Ass and Horse are different from each other but both are pet."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Page, Chapter and Book ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Page is in Chapter and Chapter is in book."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Parents, Mother and Father ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Father and mother are parents but father and mother are two opposite sexes."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Men, Rodents and Living beings ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Men and Rodents are different from one another but both these belong to living beings."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Elephants, Wolves and Animals ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Elephant and Wolves bear no relationship to each other while both are animals."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between dogs, pet animals and animals ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Some dogs are pet animals but dogs and pet both are animals."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Teacher, Parents and Guardians ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Sailor, Ship and Ocean ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "As ship is in the ocean in the same way sailor is in the ship."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Gold, Metal and Zinc ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Gold and Zinc are different from each other but both are metal."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Professors, Doctors and Men ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Some doctors may be professors and vice-versa.\nSome professors may be men and vice-versa.\nSome doctors may be men and vice-versa.\nSome doctors may be men and professors as well."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Teacher, Men and Women ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Men and Women are different from each other but some men may be teachers and some women may be teachers."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Oil, Wick and Lamp ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Oil and Wick are different from each other but they both are used in lamp."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Football, Player and Field ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Football, Players and Field all are different."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Sweets, Rasagulla and Apple ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Rasagulla is one of the sweets while apple is different from these."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Mammal, Cow and Bat ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Cow and Bat are different from each other but both are mammal."}, {"question": "Which of the following diagrams indicates the best relation between Paper, Stationery and Ink ?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Paper and Ink are different from one another but both these belong to stationery."}]]}